Ben Cuan

I am a student developer pursuing an education in Computer Science and Psychology. I specialize in frontend development and especially enjoy developing responsive and simple user interfaces in a variety of applications, including websites and games.

hello@bencuan.me



https://bencuan.me



Cupertino, CA



64bitpandas



bencuan

Education

University of California, Berkeley

August 2019 to Present | Cupertino, CA

Intended Computer Science major in the College of Letters and Science; currently starting my first semester.

Monta Vista High School

August 2015 to June 2019 | Cupertino, CA

Concurrently enrolled at De Anza College. Unweighted GPA: 3.97

Experience

Bananium Labs - Director of Operations

November 2017 to Present | Cupertino, CA | bananiumlabs.com

Cofounded and currently oversee two computer development projects at Bananium Labs, a 501(c)(3) nonprofit organization with the purpose of providing educational and monetary resources to aspiring developers.

LaunchHacks - Lead Director

June 2018 to April 2019 | Monta Vista High School | launchhacks.tech

Directed a team of 10 to organize a hackathon for approximately 200 high school students, which involved contacting sponsors, designing a website from scratch, and coordinating logistics such as catering and venue reservation.

Two Terabyte Studios - Cofounder and Code Lead

August 2016 to Present | Monta Vista High School | bananiumlabs.com/2tbs

Cofounded and led a game development club which provides students the resources to collaborate and develop video games as a team.

Projects

Frontend Web Development

Main contributor to websites for LaunchHacks, Bananium Labs, and 2TBS; contributed to the MVRT website (mvrt.com); more projects are showcased on my comprehensive portfolio website, bencuan.me.

Game Development

Participated in several Game Jams and published three small-scale games (It's Rude To Point, Bullet Heaven, Squadron Dragon). Currently developing AtomBlast, a team-based multiplayer game where players must craft compounds from atoms and defeat the opposing teams.

Hackathon Projects

Attended 8 hackathons where I developed impactful software and hardware projects such as CarrotCane, an affordable cane attachment for the visually impaired, and AudiSea, a virtual reality audio visualizer; four of my projects won awards.

Skills

Web Based Technologies

JavaScript and TypeScript

HTML and CSS

Angular

React

Node.js

Firebase

JQuery

Computer Graphics and Rendering

Unity (C#)

AFrame/WebVR

Blender

PixiJS

Other Programming Experience

Java

Python

Octave/Matlab

Awards

1st Place at TinoHacks

April 2018

4th Place at MenloHacks

March 2018

4th Place at Pioneer Hacks

March 2018

Best Website at Firebird Hacks

November 2017